The Dawn is a horror, thriller film directed by Brandon Slagle.
Following the murder of her family at the hands of her father in the wake
of World War I, a young woman is sent to live in a convent.
However, the demons that plagued her father follow,
reawakening the nightmares of her past.
Young Rose, played by Teilor Grubbs.
Father Theodore, played by David Goryl.
William, played by Jonathan Bennett.
Rose, played by Devanny Pinn.
Red Dawn is a 1984 American action drama film directed by John Milius, from a screenplay
co-written with Kevin Reynolds, and starring Patrick Swayze, Charlie Sheen, C.
Thomas Howell, Lea Thompson and Jennifer Grey, with supporting roles played by Ben Johnson,
Darren Dalton, Harry Dean Stanton, Ron O'Neal, William Smith and Powers Boothe.
Set during a fictional World War III between an increasingly isolated United States and the Soviet Union, the film follows a group of
teenage guerrillas, known as the Wolverines, fighting against a Soviet-backed Latin American invasion force in Colorado.
Despite mixed reviews from critics, the film became a commercial
success, grossing $38 million against a budget of $17 million.
It was the first film to be released in the United States with a PG-13 rating
under the modified rating system introduced on July 1, 1984.
A remake was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of minnesota, novice, orphan train.
The tone is dark and intense.